## ROBERT D. BACKUS

215 Surrey Rd. Chalfont PA 18914 | 201-218-8112, bob.backus@gmail.com

## PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

Solid background in differentiating instruction with strong emphasis on building relationships and attention to detail. Understand the relevance of providing individuals information within a timeline, especially when meeting a student's goals. Consistently exceed expectations of supervisors and peers. Experienced in handling unexpected situations with positive results within a classroom setting. Developed and implemented standardized policies and procedures.

#### **EDUCATION**

### Delaware Valley College, Doylestown PA

M.S. Educational Leadership, School Administration

anticipated 2016

 Relevant coursework: School Law, Educational Trends and Development, Supervising Diverse Groups, Principals, Methods, Development, and Assessment of Curriculum

Teaching Certificate Internship Program (7-12)

2012

- Relevant coursework: Foundations in Education, Educational Psychology, Instructional Methods and Assessment,
  Developmental Disabilities, Literacy in the Content Area, English Language Learners and the Multicultural Classroom, and Differentiated Instruction.
- Completed over 70 hours of classroom observation in multiple educational outlets.

## Rutgers, The State University of New Jersey, New Brunswick NJ

B.A. History 1999

### Ocean County College, Toms River NJ

A.A.S. Business

## CERTIFICATION AND CREDENTIALS

- Intern Teaching Certificate Level 1 (pending)
- Praxis II Social Studies 5081 7-12 Content Knowledge: Qualifying Score
- FBI Clearance (current), PA State Clearance (current), PA Child Abuse Clearance (current)

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## Sacred Heart School, Jersey City NJ

2001-2002

Teacher 7-8 Social Studies, Literature

- Developed comprehensive study plans for social studies and literature curriculum.
- Differentiated instructions methods to accommodate individuals learning styles
- Member of Middle States Committee: Created and developed lesson plans to meet requirements for Middle States Accreditation
- Liaison between Social Studies group and the rest of the committee

### Daymart Management, DBA Gecko Hospitality Chalfont PA

2012-Present

Corporate Recruiter

### CRM Restaurant Partners, DBA Cosi, Jersey City NJ

2006-2010

Catering Manager

## Hudson County Community College, Jersey City NJ

2002-2006

Assistant to the Dean-Math, Science, Technology, and Allied Health

### PROFESSIONAL ASSOCIATIONS/VOLUNTEERISM

March for Babies, Team Captain

Phi Chi of DKE Alumni Association, President, Board of Trustees